# **Gabriel Pivaro**

gfp.1@hotmail.com | Phone: 832-570-6542 | Houston, Tx 77012

Portfolio: <u>gpivaro.com</u> | LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/gabriel-pivaro</u> | Github: <u>github.com/gpivaro</u> Google Scholar (Academic Research Papers): <u>scholar.google.com/citations?user=410r\_NUAAAAJ</u>

### **SUMMARY**

Software developer with a Bachelor's in Math and Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering. Received certification in data analytics from Rice University with advanced skills in Python, MATLAB, SQL implementation, and web development. Proven records of applying statistical analysis and predictive modeling to generate simulations to support academic research and business analysis. Excellent written, oral communication, and presentation skills. Enthusiastic to solve complex problems that require mathematical modeling, hardware integration, and full-stack web development applications.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Frontend: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Plotly.js, D3.js, Chart.js, Leafleat.js
- Backend: Python Flask/Django, .NET core, MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Linux bash, and cloud technologies (AWS)
- Statistical Analysis: scikit-learn, Pandas, TensorFlow, Excel, MATLAB, MATHEMATICA, STATISTICA
- Research: Authored over 15 research papers with statistical analyzes and Monte Carlo simulation
- Teaching: Created student material and instructed Statistics undergraduate course and Telecom courses
- Hardware: Raspberry Pi automation hobbyist, Linux servers (Debian, Ubuntu), Software Defined Radio (SDR)

#### **PROJECTS**

Earthquakes Sentinel - gpivaro.github.io/leaflet-challenge/ | github.com/gpivaro/leaflet-challenge

Interactive web application that displays all the earthquakes of the last 7 days from the USGS

- Designed a web app to visualize and interact with data about earthquakes and tectonic plates.
- Technologies used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, API, Leaflet.JS

Global Air Traffic Live Tracker - gpivaro.github.io/Project 2 | gpivaro.com/airtraffic/

Full-stack web app that exhibits live air traffic information about air crafts and airports all over the world

- Led a team to create an application to extract, transform and display air traffic data
- Technologies used: MySQL, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Linux batch script, Linux cloud server

Find Your Dream Home - gpivaro.github.io/Project 3 | find-your-dream-home.herokuapp.com/

Full-stack web app that integrates Machine Learning (K-means technique) to create a real estate recommendation system

- Designed the backend using Python Flask to scrap real estate and cluster it by price range and location, storing it into a MySQL database. The frontend logs the users and recommends houses based on previous user's choices
- Tools used: MySQL, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Heroku server

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Technology Support Specialist, Woodforest National Bank, Houston, Tx

11/2019 - present

- Developed an Excel VBA macro to automate tasks that saves 1h of manpower per day and mitigate errors
- Developed Python scripts to automate the removal of over 3,000 former users saving over 20h over manpower
- Achieved a resolution rate higher than 97% in IT-related problems (standard is 85%)

Wireless Communication Researcher, National Institute of Telecommunications, Brazil

06/2016 - 05/2018

- Received substantial monetary funds for research projects by writing a request for proposal project
- Integrated hardware and software to develop an apparatus to investigate wireless channel propagation

**Visiting Scholar** at Electrical and Computational Engineering, Rice University, Houston, Tx

03/2015 - 03/2016

• Co-authored scientific paper published in a world-class scientific journal

### **EDUCATION**

Data Analytics & Visualization Boot Camp | Rice University, Houston, Tx Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering | State University of Campinas, Brazil Bachelor's degree in Mathematics | Sao Paulo State University, Brazil

01/2021